We've already walked through the first two steps in the last video.
لقد تحدثنا عن أول عنصرين في الفيديو الأخير.
Now I'm going to show you a couple of things you could have experimented with.
والآن سأوضح لك أمرين ربما تكون قد جربتهما.
I would like to change the initial quantity value so
أريد تغيير القيمة الأولية للكمية
that when the app launches it shows up as zero instead of two.
ولذا عند بدء تشغيل التطبيق تظهر القيمة 0 بدلًا من 2.
The way I can do that is to modify this global quantity variable
ولفعل ذلك، يجب أن أقوم بتعديل متغير الكمية العام
to be initialized at zero.
حيث تتم تهيئته عند 0.
Then the increment and decrement method should work just fine.
وبعد ذلك يجب أن تعمل وظيفتي الزيادة والتقليل على نحوٍ جيد.
When the increment method is called,
عند استدعاء وظيفة الزيادة،
it will use the latest quantity value and just add one.
ستستخدم قيمة الكمية الأحدث وإضافة 1 فقط.
When the decrement method is called, it will just decrease the quantity by one.
عند استدعاء وظيفة التقليل، فقط ستقوم بتقليل القيمة بمقدار 1.
Let's go ahead and try this out now.
هيا بنا نكمل ونجرب ذلك الآن.
That looks weird.
هذا يبدو غريبا.
I wanted it to show up at zero.
كنت أريده أن يعرض القيمة 0.
If I click the plus button, it's weird, it goes to one,
عند النقر فوق الزر +، من الغريب أن يذهب إلى 1،
which seems to have decreased it, but now it starts to increase.
والتي تبدو أنها قد انخفضت، ولكن الآن تبدأ في الزيادة.
So it seems like these buttons are working, but for
لذلك يبدو أن هذه الأزرار تعمل،
some reason the initial value was wrong.
ولكن لسبب ما كانت القيمة الأولية خاطئة.
Oh, we forgot to change the activity main layout file.
حسنًا، نسينا تغيير ملف مخطط النشاط الرئيسي.
In this layout we have a text view that says the initial text
في هذا المخطط، لدينا عرض نص يقول أن
quantity value is two.
القيمة الأولية لكمية النص هي 2.
That should fix our problem with the two showing up when the app launches.
ويجب أن يحل هذا مشكلتنا مع القيمة 2 تظهر عند إطلاق التطبيق.
Cool. Now it shows up
رائع. يظهر الآن على الشاشة
as initial quantity of zero.
الكمية الأولية 0.
Then if I hit increase, it updates properly.
وبعد ذلك، عند الضغط على زيادة، يتم التحديث على نحوٍ صحيح.
If I hit decrease, it also updates properly.
وعند الضغط على تقليل، يتم التحديث أيضًا على نحوٍ
You can see that it's a little tricky that we have the initial quantity
قد ترى أنه من الصعب قليلا أن
value in two places.
القيمة الأولية للكمية موجودة في مكانين.
Having two places in the code that represent the same thing
وجود مكانين في الكود الذي يمثل الشيء ذاته
can be a source of bugs in the future, like we just saw now.
قد يكون مصدرًا للأخطاء في المستقبل، مثل التي رأيناها الآن.
An advanced way to solve this problem is to have the main activity actually
هناك طريقة متقدمة لحل هذه المشكلة
display the quantity of zero immediately when the app launches,
وهي أن يعرض النشاط الرئيسي الكمية 0 فورًا عند بدء تشغيل التطبيق،
instead of relying on the layout to have an initial value.
بدلًا من الاعتماد على أن يكون للمخطط قيمة أولية.
That way the single source of truth would be this global variable.
وبهذه الطريقة يكون المصدر الوحيد للحقيقة هذا المتغير العام.
But don't worry about that now.
ولكن لا تقلق بشأن ذلك الآن.
That's more of an advanced thing that you can do after Lesson 3.
هناك أكثر من شيء متقدم يمكنك القيام به بعد الدرس الثالث.
The other way we can experiment with the code is to have the plus button
الطريقة الأخرى التي يمكننا تجربتها مع الكود هو أن يقوم الزر +
double the number of coffees ordered each time and
بمضاعفة عدد أكواب القهوة المطلوبة كل مرة
have the minus button half the number of coffees each time.
والزر - بانتصاف عدد أكواب القهوة المطلوبة كل مرة.
Let's start with an initial quantity of two, so
هيا نبدأ مع الكمية الأولية 2،
that if we hit the minus button first, we can at least cut this in half once.
ولذا عند الضغط على الزر - أولًا، يمكننا على الأقل تقليل العدد إلى النصف مرة واحدة.
When the increment method is called,
عند استدعاء وظيفة الزيادة،
we want to double the number of coffees ordered.
فنحن نريد مضاعفة عدد أكواب القهوة المطلوبة.
We should take the current quantity and then multiply it by two.
يجب أن نأخذ الكمية الحالية ثم مضاعفتها.
That gets updated to be the new quantity value and
وهذا التحديث من شأنه الوصول إلى قيمة الكمية الجديدة
then we display that to the screen.
ثم نعرضعها على الشاشة.
On the other hand, we have the decrement method.
على الجانب الآخر، لدينا وظيفة التقليل.
For the decrement method, we want to cut the number of coffees ordered in half.
بالنسبة لوظيفة التقليل، نريد تقليل عدد أكواب القهوة المطلوبة إلى النصف.
So we can take the current quantity and then divide it by two.
ومن ثم يمكننا أخذ الكمية الحالية ثم قسمتها على 2.
That will be the new quantity value.
وهذا سيكون قيمة الكمية الجديدة.
And we display that to the screen.
ونعرضعها على الشاشة.
Let's try it out.
هيا نجربها الآن.
You can see how it can be a source of error every time you want
يمكنك رؤية كيف أنها من الممكن أن تكون مصدرًا للأخطاء في كل مرة
to change the initial quantity value.
تريد فيها تغيير القيمة الأولية للكمية.
You have to change it in both places.
عليك تغييرها في كلا المكانين.
Let's run the app now.
هيا نشغل التطبيق الآن.
Okay.
حسنًا.
It starts off at an initial quantity of two.
التطبيق يبدأ التشغيل والكمية الأولية 2.
If I hit plus, it should double the quantity each time.
عند الضغط على +، يجب أن يضاعف الكمية في كل مرة.
Cool. And it does.
رائع. وها هو يفعلها.
If I hit the minus button,
وعند الضغط على الزر -،
it should cut the number of coffees ordered in half each time.
يجب أن يقل عدد أكواب القهوة المطلوب إلى النصف في كل مرة.
And it works.
وها هو يفعلها.
If I run it in the debugger, you can see how it updates the variables each time.
وعند التشغيل في متعقب الأخطاء، يمكنك رؤية كيف يقوم بتحديث المتغيرات في كل مرة.
The quantity value starts off at two, and then it updates to four.
تبدأ قيمة الكمية بالقيمة 2، ثم يتم تحديثها إلى 4.
And then the quantity starts off at four, and
وبعد ذلك تبدأ الكمية مع القيمة 4،
then it updates to eight and so on.
ثم يتم تحديثها إلى 8 وهكذا.
I'm sure you came up with much more creative ways to play around with this
أنا متأكدة أنك استنتجت طرقًا أكثر إبداعًا للتعامل مع
quantity picker.
ملتقط الكمية.
Hopefully that helped you better understand the use of global variables.
نأمل أن يساعدك ذلك في فهم أفضل لاستخدام المتغيرات العامة.
But if I hit the order button, it doesn't show me the price for
عند الضغط على زر "طلب"، لا تظهر لي السعر
that number of coffees ordered.
للعدد المطلوب من أكواب القهوة.
Let's fix that in the next video.
دعونا نصلح ذلك في الفيديو التالي.